A Guide to the Additional Papers of Jefferson C. Grinnalds, 1922-1965
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Additional Papers of Jefferson C. Grinnalds 1922-1965
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
6879-h
This collection consists of 30 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
These papers were the gift of Jefferson Cleveland Grinnalds, 7810 Overbrook Road, Ruxton, Maryland, through the Rare Book Department of Alderman Library, January 1975.
Biographical/Historical Information
Mr. Grinnalds was a member of the University of Virginia Engineering Class of 1907. During the subsequent years, he has been active as a pioneer of city planning and zoning, mainly in the Baltimore, Maryland area, and as a philanthropist active in U. Va. Alumni affairs.
Scope and Content Information
These additional papers of Jefferson C. Grinnalds, are the latest of several deposits of personal papers made by Mr. Grinnalds. This portion of his papers includes material from the years 1922 through 1965, and occupies two shelf feet.
A bound volume, Wills and Administrations, in undoubtedly the most important item. The genealogical material consists mainly of charts and notes on various American families to which Mr. Grinnalds is related, carring their ancestry back to European origins in many cases. Photographs consist of one comic picture of two unidentified young men, ca. 1900-10; one postcard, site unknown; and photocopies of Mr. Grinnalds' diplomas.
The importance of this collection derives chiefly from the articles on city planning, and from the genealogical notes. The material on the University of Virginia may be of some value to a University historian.
Organization
The collection has been extensively rearranged, placed in permanent folders, and divided into five series according to content. These are: correspondence, professional articles by Mr. Grinnalds, printed material, genealogical material, and photographs. Correspondence deals mainly with University of Virginia alumni activities, and with the Lake Placid Club. The professional articles concern various aspects of city planning during Mr. Grinnalds' career. Miscellaneous printed materials, mainly pamphlets, have been gathered together. Alumni material makes up the largest quantity.
Contents List
- Baltimore Cty College - Alumni 1954 (Box 1)
- Carmine, Mildred C. 1958-1960 (Box 1)
- City Planning - University of Virginia 1962 (Box 1)
- City Planning - Harvard School of 1930-1931 (Box 1)
- City Planning - John Hopkins University ca. 1964 (Box 1)
- Grinnalds Scholarship - University of Virginia 1964 (Box 1)
- Ice Club of Baltimore 1960-1964 (Box 1)
- Lake Placid Club ca. 1955-1965 (Box 1)
- Lake Placid Club 1961-1965, 5 folders (Box 2)
- Lake Placid Club - Scholarship 1963-1964 (Box 2)
- University of Virginia - Alumni Fund 1941-1943 (Box 2)
- University of Virginia - Alumni Fund 1943-1944 (Box 3)
- University of Virginia - Alumni 1948-1954 (Box 3)
- University of Virginia - Engineering Alumni 1949-1956 (Box 3)
- University of Virginia - Alumni 1955-1962, 4 folders (Box 3)
- University of Virginia - Alumni 1963 & 1965, 2 folders (Box 4)
- Miscellaneous Personal Correspondence and Newspaper Clippings 1956-1963 (Box 4)
- Xerox copies of Planning Reports by Mr. Grinnalds ca. 1940, 2 folders (Box 4)
- Printed Material, A-D 1922-1924 (Box 4)
- Printed Material, P-Z 1948-1950 (Box 5)
- Genealogical notebook kept by Mr. Grinnalds n. d. (Box 5)
- Wills, and Administrations, Accomack County, Va., 1663-1800 1931 (Box 5)
- Maryland Genealogical Society 1961-1964 (Box 5)
- Annotated Finding List of Genealogical Materials in the Baltimore County Public Library n. d. (Box 5)
- Genealogical Notes, Vital Records of Norwich, Conn. n. d. (Box 5)
- Miscellaneous Genealogical Material n. d. (Box 5)
- Genealogical Charts and Notes, A-D n. d. (Box 5)
- Genealogical Charts and Notes, E-H n. d. (Box 5)
- Genealogical Charts and Notes, J-W n. d. (Box 6)
- Photographs and Diplomas n. d. (Box 6)